Abenezer Addisu



Contact

Address:

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Date of Birth:

March 03, 1998 G.C

Phone:

+251-932-994-194

+251-904-209-242

Email:

abenezeraddisu24@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/abenzeraddisu/

Languages

English
Amharic
Oromifa
Sign Language

Summary

Abenezer Addisu Ayana is Full Stack Developer Passionate about Computer Sciences, Innovation and Technology with 19+ months work experience on design and development. Ability to think through a problem coupled with the confidence to make ideas heard.

Experience

Intern Website Developer

Addis Ababa Road Traffic Manag't Agency – July 24 to sept 03 2019

 Design and Develop a website with dual language for AARTMA (Addis Ababa road traffic management agency)

IT Technician – Aug 2020 to April 2021

Lima Manufacturing, Addis Ababa.

 Set up and configure new equipment and system for an organization and train computer users on new systems by performing technical demonstrations to acquaint them with operational procedures.

Web Developer – Nov 2021 to present

Earald Trading & ICT Technology, Addis Ababa

- Design and Develop User friendly, dynamic website optimized for Search engines that ensured high traffic and page view
- Updating and Fixing Bugs from Existing websites
- Cooperate with designers and senior developer to manage large, complex design projects for corporate clients.

Freelancer - Mar 2020 to Present

 I work and Participate over 15+ projects as Digital Marketer, Graphics Designer and Web Developer

Projects

- ✓ Erq maed Radio Program Content management system (CMS) They are Radio program producer working on human psychology and personal development, We building a platform where they can easily post their programs and also their clients can access and get their programs
- ✓ Nebert Property Management PLC Property Management System (ERP) for their work to easily manage multiple buildings and rooms to rent and sale from a single system.
- ✓ Ashagari Consultant Content Management System (CMS) to easily post their training programs and also their clients can access More information about training they want
- ✓ ImpactET School Management System: for Schools to manage School branch, Student, Staffs, Exam, Record and more also connect School, Parents and Student Easily
- ✓ Brana Audio Books This project focus on Developing Web app and producing Audio books to easily get Audiobook and Podcasts easily (in progress)

Technical Skill

- ✓ C++
- ✓ HTML
- ✓ CSS / Bootstrap
- ✓ React
- ✓ Node Js
- ✓ PHP / Laravel
- ✓ Flutter / Dart
- ✓ Android Studio
- ✓ Git / Github
- ✓ Wordpress
- ✓ Digital Marketing
- ✓ Graphics Design

Certificates

Digital Marketing:

- Digital Marketing Google Certification
- Netib Marketing and Consultant

Full Stack web Developer MERN

- Coursera
- Free Code Camp
- Evangadi Tech



Skill Highlights

- Team Work
- Decision maker
- Complex problem solver
- Creative design
- Innovative
- Service-focused

Education

Bachelor of Science: **Computer Science** – Oct 2016 – Jan 28, 2021 **Ambo University**, Ethiopia

High School and Preparatory: September 2012 – July 2016 **Bulbula Secondary & preparatory school**, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

References

Dr. L. Velmurugan, M.C.A, M.Phil (PhD)

• Ambo University Hachalu hundessa Campus - Computer Science department Professor and Lecturer.

Tel:-+251965023868

Mr. Naol Bekele Defarsha (Assistant Professor)

• Ambo University Hachalu hundessa Campus - Computer Science department Professor and Lecturer.

Tel:-+251923468099

Dr. Eyosiyas Assefa (MD)

CEO, Birrforex Trading Consultancy .
 Email: josiah.AG@birrforex.com

Natnael. T

• CEO, Eralad Trading and ICT Technology .

Tel:-+25192282445

Leadership and Volunteer

Team Leader and Coordinator:

✓ EvaSU (Ethiopian Evangelical Students Union)

Volunteer Translator:

✓ DEAF – REACH Ethiopia